Guide to the Henry Noble MacCracken Papers, 1907 - circa 1968
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES X. PERSONAL ORGANIZATIONS, 1915-1946
  - Personal Organizations, 1941-1946
    - Poughkeepsie Broadcasting Corp. (Folder 95.9)
    - Community Chest of Poughkeepsie (Folder 95.10)
    - Poughkeepsie United War Fund (Folder 95.11)
    - Ulster-Irish Society (Folder 95.12)
    - United Service Organization (Folder 95.13)
    - War Chest of Poughkeepsie (Folder 95.14)
    - War Chest of Poughkeepsie (Folder 95.15)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1939-1946
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Folder 95.16)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Folder 95.17)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Aug. 1940 - Dec 1940 (Folder 95.18)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Aug 1942 (Folder 95.19)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Aug 1942 (Folder 95.20)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Aug 1942 (Folder 95.21)
    - Trip for National Conference of Christians and Jews, Dec 1945 (Folder 95.22)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, (Jan 1, 1941 -) (Folder 95.23)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Dr. Aydelotte (Folder 95.24)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Commission on Educational Organization (Folder 95.25)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Commission on Human Rights (Folder 96.1)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Comm. of Writers (Folder 96.2)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - "Inside America" (Folder 96.3)
    - Manuscript of Dr. Landis' Booklet for Youth (Folder 96.4)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - New Haven Office (Folder 96.5)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Misc. (Folder 96.6)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Printed Materials (Folder 96.7)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews - Printed Materials (Folder 96.8)
- SERIES XI. PERSONAL and MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE and BUSINESS, 1915-1946
  - Personal, 1915-1921
    - A (Folder 96.9)
    - A - Misc. Outside (Folder 96.10)
    - B - Misc. Outside (Folder 96.11)
    - B (Folder 96.12)
    - B - Personal (Folder 96.13)
    - C (Folder 96.14)
    - C (Folder 96.15)
    - C- Misc. Outside (Folder 96.16)
    - D (Folder 96.17)
    - D, E (Folder 96.18)
    - E (Folder 96.19)
    - F (Folder 96.20)
    - G (Folder 96.21)
    - F, G (Folder 97.1)
    - H - Misc. Outside (Folder 97.2)
    - H (Folder 97.3)
    - H (Folder 97.4)
    - I (Folder 97.5)
    - I, J, K (Folder 97.6)
    - J (Folder 97.7)
    - K (Folder 97.8)
    - L (Folder 97.9)
    - L (Folder 97.10)
    - M (Folder 97.11)
    - M (Folder 97.12)
    - N (Folder 97.13)
    - N (Folder 97.14)
    - O (Folder 97.15)
    - O, P (Folder 97.16)
    - Owings, Chloe (Folder 97.17)
    - P (Folder 97.18)
    - P (Folder 97.19)
    - Q, R (Folder 97.20)
    - R (Folder 97.21)
    - R - Misc. Outside (Folder 97.22)
    - S (Folder 97.23)
    - S (Folder 97.24)
    - T - Misc. Outside (Folder 98.1)
    - T, U, and V (Folder 98.2)
    - T (Folder 98.3)
    - Peter H. Troy (Folder 98.4)
    - U, V (Folder 98.5)
    - V (Folder 98.6)
    - W (Folder 98.7)
    - W, Y (Folder 98.8)
    - Y (Folder 98.9)
    - Z - Personal (Folder 98.10)
    - From President to Secretary (Folder 98.11)
    - Automobiles (Folder 98.12)
    - Bank Deposits (Folder 98.13)
    - Books Ordered (Folder 98.14)
    - Colt-Stratton Co. (Folder 98.15)
    - Ethics Book (Folder 98.16)
    - Guaranty Trust Co. (Folder 98.17)
    - Guaranty Trust Co. (Folder 98.18)
    - Income Tax, 1919 (Folder 98.19)
    - Insurance (Folder 98.20)
    - Irish Situation (Folder 98.21)
    - Colleges (Pine Hill) and Summer Homes (Folder 98.22)
    - Poughkeepsie Trust Co. (Folder 98.23)
    - Prescription for Eyes (Folder 98.24)
    - Re: Religio Magistri (Folder 98.25)
    - Royalties (Folder 98.26)
  - Personal, Aug 1921 - July 1924
    - A - Personal (Folder 98.27)
    - B - Personal (Folder 98.28)
    - C - Personal (Folder 98.29)
    - D - Personal (Folder 99.1)
    - E - Personal (Folder 99.2)
    - F - Personal (Folder 99.3)
    - G - Personal (Folder 99.4)
    - H - Personal (Folder 99.5)
    - I - Personal (Folder 99.6)
    - J - Personal (Folder 99.7)
    - K - Personal (Folder 99.8)
    - L - Personal (Folder 99.9)
    - M - Personal (Folder 99.10)
    - N - Personal (Folder 99.11)
    - O - Personal (Folder 99.12)
    - P - Personal (Folder 99.13)
    - R - Personal (Folder 99.14)
    - S - Personal (Folder 99.15)
    - S - Personal (Folder 99.16)
    - T - Personal (Folder 99.17)
    - U - Personal (Folder 99.18)
    - V - Personal (Folder 99.19)
    - W - Personal (Folder 99.20)
    - W - Personal (Folder 99.21)
    - Y - Personal (Folder 99.22)
    - Y, Z - Personal (Folder 99.23)
    - Album (Folder 99.24)
    - Automobile (Folder 99.25)
    - Book - Europe Guides the Way (Folder 99.26)
    - Books Ordered (Folder 99.27)
    - Bratislava (Folder 99.28)
    - European Tour of Universities—Planning, (1922) (Folder 99.29)
    - European Tour of Universities—Itinerary, (1922) (Folder 99.30)
    - European Tour of Universities—Typed Transcipts of Letters Home, (1922) (Folder 99.31)
    - European Tour of Universities—Letters Home, (Sept - Oct 1922) (Folder 99.32)
    - European Tour of Universities—Letters Home, (Nov 1922 (Folder 99.33)
    - European Tour of Universities—Letters Home, (Dec 1922) (Folder 99.34)
    - European Tour of Universities—Letters Home, (Jan 1923, n.d.) (Folder 99.35)
    - Guaranty Trust Co. (Folder 100.1)
    - Insurance (Folder 100.2)
    - Irish Question (Folder 100.3)
    - Letters of Introduction (Folder 100.4)
    - Paintings from Cracow (Folder 100.5)
    - Poughkeepsie Trust Co. (Folder 100.6)
    - Relief Appeals (Folder 100.7)
    - Royalties (Folder 100.8)
    - Russian Books (Folder 100.9)
    - Steamship Lines (Folder 100.10)
    - Summer Homes (Folder 100.11)
    - Peter H. Troy (Folder 100.12)
  - Personal, 1923-1926
    - A - Personal (Folder 100.13)
    - B - Personal (Folder 100.14)
    - C - Personal (Folder 100.15)
    - D - Personal (Folder 100.16)
    - E - Personal (Folder 100.17)
    - F - Personal (Folder 100.18)
    - G - Personal (Folder 100.19)
    - H - Personal (Folder 100.20)
    - I - Personal (Folder 100.21)
    - J - Personal (Folder 100.22)
    - K - Personal (Folder 100.23)
    - L - Personal (Folder 100.24)
    - M - Personal (Folder 100.25)
    - N - Personal (Folder 100.26)
    - O - Personal (Folder 100.27)
    - P - Personal (Folder 100.28)
    - Q - Personal (Folder 100.29)
    - R - Personal (Folder 100.30)
    - T - Personal (Folder 100.31)
    - Peter H. Troy, 1926 (Folder 100.32)
    - U - Personal (Folder 100.33)
    - V - Personal (Folder 100.34)
    - W - Personal (Folder 100.35)
    - Y - Personal (Folder 101.1)
    - Z - Personal (Folder 101.2)
    - Automobile (Folder 101.3)
    - Bank Deposits (Folder 101.4)
    - Bankers Trust Co. (Folder 101.5)
    - Community Trust of Poughkeepsie (Folder 101.6)
    - Cooperative Book Shop - Books Purchased and Correspondence (Folder 101.7)
    - European Trip - Summer, 1925 (Folder 101.8)
    - Insurance (Folder 101.9)
    - Raoul Nadeau (Folder 101.10)
    - Personal Property (Folder 101.11)
    - Personal securities (Folder 101.12)
    - Photographs (Folder 101.13)
    - Photographs of Yelping Hill (Folder 101.14)
    - Pictures - Misc. (Folder 101.15)
    - Poughkeepsie Automobile Club (Folder 101.16)
    - Poughkeepsie Trust Co. (Folder 101.17)
    - Royalties (Folder 101.18)
    - Vassar Brothers Hospital (Folder 101.19)
    - Vassar Bank (Folder 101.20)
  - Personal, 1927-1940
    - Atlantic Funding Corporation (Folder 101.21)
    - Automobile (Folder 101.22)
    - Car Theft (Folder 101.23)
    - Bank Deposits (Folder 101.24)
    - W.H. Baker, Inc. (Folder 101.25)
    - Bankers Trust Co. (Folder 101.26)
    - Books Loaned (Folder 101.27)
    - Community Trust (Folder 101.28)
    - Community Trust of Poughkeepsie (Folder 101.29)
    - Cooperative Book Shop - Books Purchased and Correspondence (Folder 101.30)
    - Financial File - Misc. (Folder 101.31)
    - Misc. Financial, 1927 (Folder 101.32)
    - Misc. Financial, 1927 (Folder 101.33)
    - Financial Misc. (Folder 101.34)
    - Misc. Financial (Folder 101.35)
    - Misc. Financial (Folder 101.36)
    - Holdings (Folder 101.37)
    - Holdings (Folder 101.38)
    - Holdings (Folder 101.39)
    - Hornyback (Folder 101.40)
    - Hotels (Folder 101.41)
    - Internal Revenue Tax (Folder 101.42)
    - Income Tax (Folder 101.43)
    - Insurance (Folder 101.44)
    - Insurance - Personal (Folder 102.1)
    - Insurance (Folder 102.2)
    - Insurance (Folder 102.3)
    - Insurance (Folder 102.4)
    - Itineraries of Trips (Folder 102.5)
    - Trip Outlines (Folder 102.6)
    - European Trip, June 20, 1928 (Folder 102.7)
    - Auga, Georgia, Trip, Jan 1929 (Folder 102.8)
    - Seminar in Mexico (Folder 102.9)
    - Mexican Trip, July 1934 (Folder 102.10)
    - Livingston and Co. - Misc. (Folder 102.11)
    - M.S. Batory (Folder 102.12)
    - Photographs (Folder 102.13)
    - Poughkeepsie Trust Co. (Folder 102.14)
    - Poughkeepsie Trust Co. (Folder 102.15)
    - Poughkeepsie Trust Co. (Folder 102.16)
    - Royalties (Folder 102.17)
    - Royalties (Folder 102.18)
    - Stock Exchange (Folder 102.19)
    - Summer Camps (Folder 102.20)
    - Peter H. Troy (Folder 102.21)
    - Vassar Bank (Folder 102.22)
    - Vassar Bank (Folder 102.23)
    - Vassar Bank (Folder 102.24)
    - Vassar Bank (Folder 102.25)
    - Vassar Bank (Folder 102.26)
    - Widmann and Co. (Folder 102.27)
    - Yelping Hill (Folder 102.28)
    - Yelping Hill Association (Folder 102.29)
    - Yelping Hill Association (Folder 102.30)
    - Yelping Hill Association (Folder 102.31)
  - Personal Correspondence, Aug 1926 - Aug 1931
    - A - Personal (Folder 102.32)
    - B - Personal (Folder 102.33)
    - D - Personal (Folder 103.1)
    - E - Personal (Folder 103.2)
    - F - Personal (Folder 103.3)
    - G - Personal (Folder 103.4)
    - H - Personal (Folder 103.5)
    - I - Personal (Folder 103.6)
    - J - Personal (Folder 103.7)
    - K - Personal (Folder 103.8)
    - L - Personal (Folder 103.9)
    - M - Personal (Folder 103.10)
    - N - Personal (Folder 103.11)
    - O - Personal (Folder 103.12)
    - P - Personal (Folder 103.13)
    - R - Personal (Folder 103.14)
    - S - Personal (Folder 103.15)
    - T - Personal (Folder 103.16)
    - U, V - Personal (Folder 103.17)
    - W - Personal (Folder 103.18)
    - X, Y, and Z - Personal (Folder 103.19)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Aug 1926-1928
    - Broadcasting (Folder 103.20)
    - Carnegie Corp. (Folder 103.21)
    - Church Organizations - Misc. (Folder 103.22)
    - Cite Universitaire, Paris (Folder 103.23)
    - The Commonwealth Fund (Folder 103.24)
    - Faculty Pensions (Folder 103.25)
    - Harmon Foundation (Folder 103.26)
    - Honorary Degrees (Folder 103.27)
    - Hotels (Folder 103.28)
    - International House (Folder 103.29)
    - International University Cruise (Folder 103.30)
    - Japanese Association of America (Folder 103.31)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Folder 103.32)
    - Journal of Education (Folder 103.33)
    - The Kahn Foundation for the Foreign Travel of American Teachers (Folder 103.34)
    - The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (Folder 104.1)
    - Leopold Schepp Foundation (Folder 104.2)
    - Letchworth Village (Folder 104.3)
    - Near East College Association (Folder 104.4)
    - Near East Relief (Folder 104.5)
    - The New York Times Current Events Contest (Folder 104.6)
    - Pan American Union (Folder 104.7)
    - The Rockefeller Foundation (Folder 104.8)
    - School of Foreign Travel, Inc. (Folder 104.9)
    - United States (Folder 104.10)
    - University Travel Association (Folder 104.11)
    - A - Misc. (Folder 104.12)
    - B - Misc. (Folder 104.13)
    - C - Misc. (Folder 104.14)
    - D - Misc. (Folder 104.15)
    - E - Misc. (Folder 104.16)
    - F - Misc. (Folder 104.17)
    - G - Misc. (Folder 104.18)
    - H - Misc. (Folder 104.19)
    - I - Misc. (Folder 104.20)
    - J - Misc. (Folder 104.21)
    - K - Misc. (Folder 104.22)
    - L - Misc. (Folder 104.23)
    - M - Misc. (Folder 104.24)
    - N - Misc. (Folder 104.25)
    - O - Misc. (Folder 104.26)
    - P - Misc. (Folder 104.27)
    - Q - Misc. (Folder 104.28)
    - R - Misc. (Folder 104.29)
    - S - Misc. (Folder 104.30)
    - T - Misc. (Folder 104.31)
    - U - Misc. (Folder 104.32)
    - V - Misc. (Folder 104.33)
    - W - Misc. (Folder 104.34)
    - Y - Misc. (Folder 104.35)
    - Z - Misc. (Folder 104.36)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1928-1933
    - A - Misc. (Folder 104.37)
    - A - Misc. (Folder 104.38)
    - B - Misc. (Folder 104.39)
    - C - Misc. (Folder 104.40)
    - C - Misc. (Folder 104.41)
    - D - Misc. (Folder 105.1)
    - E - Misc. (Folder 105.2)
    - F - Misc. (Folder 105.3)
    - G - Misc. (Folder 105.4)
    - H - Misc. (Folder 105.5)
    - I - Misc. (Folder 105.6)
    - J - Misc. (Folder 105.7)
    - K - Misc. (Folder 105.8)
    - L - Misc. (Folder 105.9)
    - M - Misc. (Folder 105.10)
    - N - Misc. (Folder 105.11)
    - O - Misc. (Folder 105.12)
    - P - Misc. (Folder 105.13)
    - R - Misc. (Folder 105.14)
    - S - Misc. (Folder 105.15)
    - S - Misc. (Folder 105.16)
    - T - Misc. (Folder 105.17)
    - U - Misc. (Folder 105.18)
    - V - Misc. (Folder 105.19)
    - W - Misc. (Folder 105.20)
    - W - Misc. (Folder 105.21)
    - Y - Misc. (Folder 105.22)
    - Z - Misc. (Folder 105.23)
    - Bibliographies, 1932-1933 (Folder 105.24)
  - Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence, July 1931 - July 1936
    - Personal A (Folder 105.25)
    - A Misc. (Folder 105.26)
    - Personal B (Folder 105.27)
    - B Misc. (Folder 106.1)
    - Personal C (Folder 106.2)
    - C Misc. (Folder 106.3)
    - D Personal (Folder 106.4)
    - D Misc. (Folder 106.5)
    - E Personal (Folder 106.6)
    - E Misc. (Folder 106.7)
    - F Personal (Folder 106.8)
    - F Misc. (Folder 106.9)
    - G Personal (Folder 106.10)
    - G Misc. (Folder 106.11)
    - H Personal (Folder 106.12)
    - H Misc. (Folder 106.13)
    - I, J, K Personal (Folder 106.14)
    - I Misc. (Folder 106.15)
    - J Misc. (Folder 106.16)
    - K Misc. (Folder 106.17)
    - L Personal (Folder 106.18)
    - L Misc. (Folder 106.19)
    - M Personal (Folder 106.20)
    - M Misc. (Folder 106.21)
    - David Moorehead (Folder 106.22)
    - N Personal (Folder 106.23)
    - N Misc. (Folder 106.24)
    - O Personal (Folder 106.25)
    - O Misc. (Folder 106.26)
    - Personal P, Q (Folder 106.27)
    - P Misc. (Folder 107.1)
    - R Personal (Folder 107.2)
    - R Misc. (Folder 107.3)
    - S Personal (Folder 107.4)
    - S Misc. (Folder 107.5)
    - T Personal (Folder 107.6)
    - T Misc. (Folder 107.7)
    - U, V Personal (Folder 107.8)
    - U Misc. (Folder 107.9)
    - V Misc. (Folder 107.10)
    - W, X, Y, Z Personal (Folder 107.11)
    - W Misc. (Folder 107.12)
    - Y Misc. (Folder 107.13)
    - Z Misc. (Folder 107.14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Aug 1935 - Aug 1938
    - A - Misc. (Folder 107.15)
    - A - Misc. (Folder 107.16)
    - B - Misc. (Folder 107.17)
    - B - Misc. (Folder 107.18)
    - C - Misc. (Folder 107.19)
    - C - Misc. (Folder 107.20)
    - D - Misc. (Folder 107.21)
    - D - Misc. (Folder 107.22)
    - E - Misc. (Folder 107.23)
    - E - Misc. (Folder 107.24)
    - F - Misc. (Folder 107.25)
    - F - Misc. (Folder 107.26)
    - G - Misc. (Folder 107.27)
    - G - Misc. (Folder 107.28)
    - H - Misc. (Folder 107.29)
    - H - Misc. (Folder 107.30)
    - I - Misc. (Folder 107.31)
    - I - Misc. (Folder 107.32)
    - J - Misc. (Folder 107.33)
    - J - Misc. (Folder 107.34)
    - K - Misc. (Folder 107.35)
    - K - Misc. (Folder 107.36)
    - L - Misc. (Folder 107.37)
    - L - Misc. (Folder 107.38)
    - M - Misc. (Folder 108.1)
    - M - Misc. (Folder 108.2)
    - N - Misc. (Folder 108.3)
    - N - Misc. (Folder 108.4)
    - O - Misc. (Folder 108.5)
    - O - Misc. (Folder 108.6)
    - P - Misc. (Folder 108.7)
    - P - Misc. (Folder 108.8)
    - Q - Misc. (Folder 108.9)
    - R - Misc. (Folder 108.10)
    - R - Misc. (Folder 108.11)
    - S - Misc. (Folder 108.12)
    - S - Misc. (Folder 108.13)
    - T - Misc. (Folder 108.14)
    - T - Misc. (Folder 108.15)
    - U - Misc. (Folder 108.16)
    - V - Misc. (Folder 108.17)
    - V - Misc. (Folder 108.18)
    - W - Misc. (Folder 108.19)
    - W - Misc. (Folder 108.20)
    - X, Y, and Z - Misc. (Folder 108.21)
    - X, Y, and Z - Misc. (Folder 108.22)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1936-1940
    - Uncategorized Misc. Correspondence (Folder 108.23)
    - Personal A (Folder 108.24)
    - Personal A (Folder 108.25)
    - Personal A (Folder 108.26)
    - Personal B (Folder 108.27)
    - Personal C (Folder 108.28)
    - Personal C (Folder 108.29)
    - Personal D (Folder 108.30)
    - Personal E (Folder 108.31)
    - Personal F (Folder 108.32)
    - Personal G (Folder 108.33)
    - Personal H (Folder 108.34)
    - Personal I (Folder 108.35)
    - Personal J (Folder 109.1)
    - Personal K (Folder 109.2)
    - Personal L (Folder 109.3)
    - Personal M (Folder 109.4)
    - Personal M (Folder 109.5)
    - Personal N (Folder 109.6)
    - Personal N (Folder 109.7)
    - Personal O (Folder 109.8)
    - Personal P (Folder 109.9)
    - Personal P (Folder 109.10)
    - Personal R (Folder 109.11)
    - Personal R (Folder 109.12)
    - Personal S (Folder 109.13)
    - Personal S (Folder 109.14)
    - Personal T (Folder 109.15)
    - Personal U (Folder 109.16)
    - Personal V (Folder 109.17)
    - Personal W (Folder 109.18)
    - Personal X, Y, and Z (Folder 109.19)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1940-1943
    - Personal A (Folder 109.20)
    - Personal A (Folder 109.21)
    - Personal B (Folder 109.22)
    - Personal B (Folder 109.23)
    - Personal C (Folder 109.24)
    - Personal C (Folder 109.25)
    - Personal D (Folder 109.26)
    - Personal E (Folder 109.27)
    - Personal F (Folder 109.28)
    - Personal G (Folder 109.29)
    - Personal H (Folder 109.30)
    - Personal H (Folder 109.31)
    - Personal I (Folder 110.1)
    - Personal I (Folder 110.2)
    - Personal J (Folder 110.3)
    - Personal K (Folder 110.4)
    - Personal K (Folder 110.5)
    - Personal L (Folder 110.6)
    - Personal M (Folder 110.7)
    - Personal M (Folder 110.8)
    - Personal N (Folder 110.9)
    - Personal N (Folder 110.10)
    - Personal O (Folder 110.11)
    - Personal P and Q (Folder 110.12)
    - Personal R (Folder 110.13)
    - Personal S (Folder 110.14)
    - Personal S (Folder 110.15)
    - Personal T (Folder 110.16)
    - Personal U (Folder 110.17)
    - Personal V (Folder 110.18)
    - Personal W (Folder 110.19)
    - Personal W (Folder 110.20)
    - Personal X, Y, and Z (Folder 110.21)
  - Personal Correspondence, Aug 1943-1946
    - Personal A (Folder 110.22)
    - Personal B (Folder 110.23)
    - Personal C (Folder 110.24)
    - Personal D (Folder 110.25)
    - Personal E (Folder 110.26)
    - Personal F (Folder 110.27)
    - Personal G (Folder 110.28)
    - Personal H (Folder 110.29)
    - Personal I (Folder 110.30)
    - Personal J (Folder 110.31)
    - Personal K (Folder 110.32)
    - Personal L (Folder 110.33)
    - L Misc. (Folder 110.34)
    - Personal M (Folder 110.35)
    - Personal N (Folder 110.36)
    - Personal O (Folder 110.37)
    - Personal P and Q (Folder 110.38)
    - Personal R (Folder 110.39)
    - Personal S (Folder 110.40)
    - Personal T (Folder 110.41)
    - Personal U and V (Folder 110.42)
    - Personal W (Folder 110.43)
- SERIES XII. BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION AND PERSONAL PUBLICATIONS, 1907-1946
  - Bibliographical; Recognition; MacCracken Family
    - Attempt to get MacCracken to resign (Folder 111.1)
    - Attempt to get MacCracken to resign (Folder 111.2)
    - MacCracken - Biographical, General (Folder 111.3)
    - Biographical Notebook - MacCracken's listing of his contributions to Various Organizations (Folder 111.4)
    - Inauguration (Folder 111.5)
    - Inaugural Congratulations (Folder 111.6)
    - Congratulations A - Y (Folder 111.7-23)
    - Resignation, 1918 (Folder 111.24)
    - Resignation, 1918 (Folder 111.25)
    - Resignation, 1918 (Folder 111.26)
    - MacCracken, Henry Mitchell (Folder 111.27)
    - Letters from Intimate Friends, Alumnae, Students, and Family, 1918 (Folder 111.28)
    - Letters from Intimate Friends, Alumnae, Students, and Family, 1918 (Folder 111.29)
    - Letters from Intimate Friends, Alumnae, Students, and Family, 1918 (Folder 111.30)
    - Letters from Intimate Friends, Alumnae, Students, and Family, 1918 (Folder 111.31)
    - Letters from Faculty and Trustees, 1918 (Folder 111.32)
    - Letters from Faculty and Trustees, 1918 (Folder 111.33)
    - Letters from Faculty and Trustees, 1918 (Folder 111.34)
    - Letters from Faculty and Trustees, 1918 (Folder 111.35)
    - Return to College 1918; 54th Commencement Program (1919) (Folder 111.36)
    - Buffalo Office, 1921 (Folder 111.37)
    - Re: Invitation to be Chancellor of University of Buffalo (Folder 111.38)
    - 10th Anniversary at Vassar (Folder 111.39)
    - 20th Anniversary at Vassar (Folder 111.40)
    - 25th Anniversary at Vassar (Folder 111.41)
    - President's War Service (Folder 111.42)
    - MacCracken (Folder 111.43)
    - MacCracken (Folder 111.44)
    - Calvin MacCracken (Folder 111.45)
    - MacCracken Genealogy (Folder 111.46)
    - George Gere MacCracken (Folder 111.47)
    - MacCracken, John (Folder 111.48)
    - MacCracken, John (Folder 111.49)
    - MacCracken, John (Folder 111.50)
    - MacCracken, John (Folder 111.51)
    - MacCracken, John (Folder 111.52)
    - MacCracken, John (Folder 111.53)
    - MacCracken, Joy (Folder 111.54)
    - Pedigree (Folder 111.55)
    - Maisry MacCracken (Folder 111.56)
    - Marjorie MacCracken (Folder 111.57)
    - Letters of Sympathy (Folder 111.58)
    - Miss S.B. Dodd (Folder 111.59)
    - James Inouye (Folder 111.60)
    - Clippings - Vassar, MacCracken; 3 Programs - Speeches made, 1915-1933 (Folder 111.61)
    - Misc. Clippings, 1915-1940 (Folder 111.62)
    - Misc. Clippings, 1915-1940 (Folder 111.63)
    - Misc. Clippings, 1915-1940 (Folder 111.64)
    - Clippings - Election (Folder 111.65)
    - NYU, MacCracken Hall dedication, 1936 (Folder 112.33)
  - Publications, Speeches and Misc Professional Activities, 1907-1946
    - Publications, 1919-1926 (Folder 112.1)
    - Articles Written (Folder 112.2)
    - Articles Written (Folder 112.3)
    - "Pathfinder" Article (Folder 112.4)
    - Article "Personal View" in Alumnae Magazine (Folder 112.5)
    - Brooklyn Church and Mission Federation Speech (Folder 112.6)
    - Cantor Conteat (Folder 112.7)
    - Chaucer Manuscript (Folder 112.8)
    - Chaucer (Folder 112.9)
    - Chaucer and Lydgate (Folder 112.10)
    - Child Labor Amendment (Folder 112.11)
    - Conference on Canadian-American Affairs, June 14, 1937 (Folder 112.12)
    - Encomiums (Folder 112.13)
    - Fair Play (Folder 112.14)
    - Hand Book (Folder 112.15)
    - "Information Please" Program (Folder 112.16)
    - "5 Intelligent Women" (Folder 112.17)
    - Invitations to Speak - Declined (Folder 112.18)
    - Invitations to Speak - Declined (Folder 112.19)
    - Invitations to Speak - Declined (Folder 112.20)
    - Speaking Invitations Accepted, 1931-1932 (Folder 112.21)
    - Child Labor (Folder 112.22)
    - Religion (Folder 112.23)
    - President's Speeches, 1932-1933 (Folder 112.24)
    - Speeches (Folder 112.25)
    - "Mediaeval Casements" Lectures - see Speeches #246 (Folder 112.26)
    - Lecture on "Racism,", 1942/1943 (Folder 112.27)
    - Lydgate (Folder 112.28)
    - Lydgate's Serpent of Division (Folder 112.28a)